The idea of universal health care is often presented as a catch-all solution to America's health care problems,
often by more progressive politicians and political commentators.
So let's talk about why universal health care is not necessarily the solution that we think it is.
First of all, though, this is not necessarily an argument against universal health care.
Universal health care can be a really great thing, and people struggling to access health care in the United States
because of their financial situation is a huge problem that needs to be considered so, so much more.
In fact, statistics for overall health, life expectancy, and maternal and infant mortality
infant mortality for populations and nations that have universal health care is very promising
and consistently better than nations that do not have universal health care.
So it makes sense why so many liberal-minded Americans think universal health care is such
a great solution to America's health care problems.
But in reality, universal health care seems perfect until you're on a months-long wait
list for a surgery that has a huge impact on your life.
In other words, many universal health care systems are accompanied by exhaustion of health
care workers, lower quality of care, and extremely long lead times.
Despite its very apparent flaws, the US's market-based health care system has helped
drive medical innovation worldwide and gives patients fast access to specialists and elective
procedures.
Obviously this becomes a huge issue when healthcare is focused more on profits than patients and
that's where we see huge problems within the US healthcare system.
Basically what I'm trying to say here in this video is that the solution to the US's healthcare
problems is not black and white the way it is so often made out to be.
Every system involves trade-outs but the best solution in terms of healthcare is likely
going to look like a balance between capitalist and socialist policies.
The combination of universal coverage with private insurance and market elements pushes
that innovation that the US is so strong within the US but also gives people access despite
their financial situation.
Obviously this is easier said than done but overall it's really important just to listen
to both sides of the argument because they both have their advantages and disadvantages.
And like a lot of things in politics, the most perfect solution is going to be a balance
between both sides.
Governing from the middle isn't just a political tool used to make everyone like you, it's
a political tool that's actually effective.
So let's look at that with healthcare.
Alright, that's all she wrote.
Bye guys!